

# **Nick Rudolph**

I'm a passionate VFX artist with 10 years of experience in the video game industry. Dedicated to creating visually compelling and intensive effects that work to the specific platforms strengths and limitations. Knowledgeable of entire visual effects pipeline from conception through implementation; able to quickly learn new pipelines and make immediate contributions. I thrive on the intersection of art and technology.

## **SKILLS**

- 3DS Max, Maya, Fume FX, After Effects, Unreal 3, Unreal 4, Cascade and Shuriken particle editors, Cinematics, Node based materials, Post Effects, Unity, PhysX, 3D modeling, Mudbox and Zbrush.
- Easy going and passionate. Quick problem solver.

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

VFX Artist June 2011- January 2015 : Zombie Studios -Seattle, Washington

• Responsible for vfx for multiple titles on PC and current/next gen platforms. From particles to post effects, fluid sims, modeling props, and creating cinematics. Engines used Unreal 4, Unreal 3 and Unity.

**Environment Artist** June 2010- June2011: Microsoft R&D - Redmond, Washington

• Created 9 of the 15 environments, and vfx for the Xbox 360 title Avatar Kinect.

**Environment Artist** March 2008 – March 2010: Microsoft Xbox Live- Redmond, Washington

■ The sole environment artist on 1vs100 for Xbox 360.

**Environment Artist** July 2007 – March 2008: Handheld Games- Lynnwood, Washington

• Created environments for multiple Nintendo DS and Wii games.

**Environment/ 3D Artist** June 2007--July 2007: WXP- Seattle, Washington

• Worked contract to model texture and light props and environments for Scene It? on Xbox 360.

3D Character/Environment Artist January 2006 – June 2007: Global Wonder- Seattle

• Character cinematic animation and modeling, texturing, and rigging of 3D avatars for Logitech.

### **SHIPPED GAMES**

Blacklight Retribution, PS4, PC Zombie Studios

Daylight, PS4, PC Atlus/Zombie Studios

America's Army Proving Grounds PC US Army/Zombie Studios

Special Forces Team X, Xbox 360, PC Micropose/Zombie Studios

Frogger Hyper Arcade, PS3, Xbox 360, Wii, iOS, Android Konami/Zombie Studios

Avatar Kinect, Xbox 360 Microsoft Game Studios/MS R&D

**1vs100**, Xbox 360 Microsoft Game Studios/Xbox Live Prime Time

Scene It?. Xbox 360 WXP/Screen Life

Pirates of the Burning Sea, PC Flying Lab Software

**MS Flight Simulator X**, PC Microsoft

#### **EDUCATION**

Associate of Applied Arts in Animation - The Art Institute of Seattle 2005 with Honors

**3D Studio Max for Game Development-** Mesmer Animation Labs, 2003

Modeling for Games- Seattle Central Community College, 2001/2002

Certificate of Multimedia Design- Green River Community College 2000